<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scrum on Wil&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://wils0n.github.io/tags/scrum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scrum on Wil&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wils0n.github.io/tags/scrum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learnings from the PSM Certification at Scrum.org</title>
      <link>https://wils0n.github.io/posts/learnings-from-the-psm-certification-at-scrum.org/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wils0n.github.io/posts/learnings-from-the-psm-certification-at-scrum.org/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The daily scrum meetings are not reported events of tasks, status or to answer the 3 questions (what I did yesterday, what I do today and if I have any impediments), they are meetings to identify impediments and produce actionable plans for that day&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The daily scrum meetings are not to resolve problems, but to promote quick decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The daily scrum meeting should not exceed the 15 minutes of duration. If the team does not talk about all the User Histories (UH) it is because something is bad. To not work in many UHs instantly, focus only on the necessary ones. It Is bad practice to attack many UHs simultaneously.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The scrum team does not include roles, such as testers, UX/UI, or Technical Leads, because that encourages individual working,  not in the product value. The members of the team should find ways to help in areas where they don&amp;rsquo;t have  specialisation, because that is a skill that is expected in the members of the team. For example if there are roles like tester, they could say ‘today I can’t do anything, because I need the release of the developers&amp;rsquo;. This is an example of bad practice, because you are only focusing on an individual&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is false to say that when a  team has matured, that it is not necessarily to have a scrum master (SM). A scrum master is part of the team and should always be present.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Product Owner (PO) is not accountable for writing the UH or acceptance criteria. The product owner is accountable for the vision, clearing, sorting, final valuation of the product and management of the Product Backlog.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is a common problem that developers use a very technical language when talking with other people, but they should talk in terms of the business when dealing  with non technical members (ex: PO, SM).&#xA;In the scrum, there is no sprint zero, sprint of test, sprint of architecture, sprint of release or sprint of documentation. - If you need non-functional requirements you can add to the Definition of Done (DoD) or to the Product Backlog.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The DoD normally contains some non-functional requirements like security and levels of quality or performance, which is provided by the Organisation, or ‘if not’ it can be created by the scrum team.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is only a DoD, if there are many scrum teams. DoD creates transparency by providing everyone a shared understanding of what work was completed as part of the Increment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The DoD can be inspected in the Retrospective Sprint and it can be changed if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the Retrospective Sprint you inspect the last sprint about individuals, relations, interactions, processes, tools and DoD.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the Retrospective Sprint the product owner can participate as a member of the Scrum Team.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
